YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 9. Photographs
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. PRINTS AND NEGATIVES
  - Subseries F. Student Work
    - Programs and Projects
      - International Experiences for Students: Dialogue at the World YWCA, summer 1988 (Box 1041, Folder 12)
      - Latin American Seminar, 1965 (Box 1041, Folder 13)
      - U.S.A./U.S.S.R. Exchange, 1963, n.d. (Box 1041, Folder 14)
      - Washington Student Citizenship Seminar, 1951, n.d. (Box 1041, Folder 15)
    - Staff
      - General, 1906-51, n.d. (Box 1041, Folder 16)
      - Margaret Norton retirement scrapbook, Sep 1968 (Box 1041, Folder 17)
    - Student Associations
      - General, 1940s-80s (Box 1041, Folder 18-19)
      - Howard University scrapbook, circa 1980 (Box 1041, Folder 20)
  - Subseries G. Community Associations
    - General
      - Border Work, Texas, 1910-16 (Box 1042, Folder 1)
      - Executive Directors' meetings, 1984, 1986 (Box 1042, Folder 2)
      - Metropolitan Seminar, 1985, 1986, 1988 (Box 1042, Folder 3-5)
      - Parade Floats, YWCA and USO, 1910s-80s (Box 1042, Folder 6)
      - Rural Work and County YWCAs, 1910s-41 (Box 1042, Folder 7)
    - Buildings and Properties
      - Alabama (Box 1042, Folder 8)
      - Arizona (Box 1042, Folder 9)
      - Arkansas: Little Rock Phyllis Wheatley Club (Box 1042, Folder 10)
      - California
        - General (Box 1042, Folder 11)
        - Hollywood Studio Club (Box 1042, Folder 12)
        - Long Beach (Box 1042, Folder 13)
        - Los Angeles (Box 1042, Folder 14)
        - San Diego (Box 1042, Folder 15)
      - Colorado: Denver (Box 1042, Folder 16)
      - Connecticut (Box 1043, Folder 1)
      - District of Columbia (Box 1043, Folder 2)
      - Florida (Box 1043, Folder 3)
      - Georgia: Augusta (Box 1043, Folder 4)
      - Hawaii (Box 1043, Folder 5)
      - Idaho (Box 1043, Folder 6)
      - Illinois (Box 1043, Folder 7)
      - Indiana (Box 1043, Folder 8)
      - Iowa (Box 1043, Folder 9)
      - Kansas (Box 1043, Folder 10)
      - Kentucky: Louisville (Box 1043, Folder 11)
      - Louisiana (Box 1043, Folder 12)
      - Maryland: Baltimore (Box 1043, Folder 13)
      - Massachusetts
        - General (Box 1043, Folder 14)
        - Boston (Box 1043, Folder 15)
      - Michigan
        - General (Box 1043, Folder 16)
        - Detroit (Box 1043, Folder 17)
        - Flint (Box 1043, Folder 18)
        - Grand Rapids (Box 1043, Folder 19)
        - Lansing (Box 1043, Folder 20)
      - Minnesota
        - General (Box 1043, Folder 21)
        - Minneapolis (Box 1043, Folder 22)
      - Mississippi: Hattiesburg (Box 1043, Folder 23)
      - Missouri: St. Joseph (Box 1043, Folder 24)
      - Nebraska (Box 1043, Folder 25)
      - New Hampshire: Nashua (Box 1043, Folder 26)
      - New Jersey (Box 1044, Folder 1)
      - New York
        - General (Box 1044, Folder 2)
        - Brooklyn (Box 1044, Folder 3)
        - City of New York (Box 1044, Folder 4)
      - North Carolina (Box 1044, Folder 5)
      - North Dakota (Box 1044, Folder 6)
      - Ohio (Box 1044, Folder 7)
      - Oklahoma (Box 1044, Folder 8)
      - Oregon: Portland (Box 1044, Folder 9)
      - Pennsylvania (Box 1044, Folder 10-12)
      - Puerto Rico (Box 1044, Folder 13)
      - Rhode Island: Providence (Box 1044, Folder 14)
      - South Carolina: Sumter (Box 1044, Folder 15)
      - South Dakota (Box 1044, Folder 16)
      - Tennessee (Box 1044, Folder 17)
      - Texas
        - General (Box 1044, Folder 18)
        - Dallas, Richardson Branch: Album (Box 1044, Folder 19)
      - Virginia (Box 1045, Folder 1)
      - Washington (Box 1045, Folder 2)
      - West Virginia (Box 1045, Folder 3)
      - Wisconsin (Box 1045, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified (Box 1045, Folder 4a)
    - Groups
      - Alabama, 1910, n.d. (Box 1045, Folder 5)
      - Alaska: Anchorage, 1997 (Box 1045, Folder 6)
      - Arizona: General, circa 1960s; Douglas, n.d.; Phoenix, 1982, circa 1990s (Box 1045, Folder 7)
      - Arkansas: General, n.d.; Little Rock, circa 1990s (Box 1045, Folder 8)
      - California
        - Bonita, 1966; Capitola, n.d.; Fontana, n.d., Glendale, 1983, circa 1990s, n.d. (Box 1045, Folder 9)
        - Hollywood, 1916; Long Beach, 1975; Los Angeles, 1961-85, circa 1990s, n.d. (Box 1045, Folder 10)
        - Oakland, 1977, 1988; Orange County, circa 1995 (Box 1045, Folder 11)
        - Palo Alto, 1970; Pasadena, 1924,n.d.; Sacramento, 1986, 1996, n.d. (Box 1045, Folder 12)
        - San Diego, 1953-1976; San Francisco, 1951, 1965, circa 1980; San Gabriel, 1983; Santa Clara Valley, 1983; Santa Monica, n.d.; Watsonville, 1996 (Box 1045, Folder 13)
      - Colorado: Denver, 1970; Rocky Ford, 1932 (Box 1045, Folder 14)
      - Connecticut: Greenwich, 1976; Hartford, circa 1922-73, n.d.; New Haven, circa 1980, n.d.; Waterbury, 1976 (Box 1046, Folder 1)
      - District of Columbia, circa 1960s-96 (Box 1046, Folder 2)
      - Florida: Jacksonville, 1996; Miami, 1995; Pinellas County; St. Petersburg, 1981 (Box 1046, Folder 3)
      - Georgia: Atlanta, circa 1990, n.d., 1996; Macon; Savannah (Box 1046, Folder 4)
      - Hawaii
        - Children and Teens, 1949-72, n.d. (Box 1046, Folder 5)
        - Groups, 1934-96, n.d. (Box 1046, Folder 6)
        - Program, 1920-65 (Box 1046, Folder 7)
        - Honolulu Scrapbook (disassembled), 1929-34 (Box 1046, Folder 8)
        - Honolulu: photos from Dorothea Spellmann, 1936-41 (Box 1046, Folder 9-12)
      - Idaho: Boise, 1976 (Box 1046, Folder 13)
      - Illinois: General; Aurora; Eureka; Chicago,1987, 1996, 1910s?, 1973-96, 1993; Quincy (Box 1046, Folder 14)
      - Indiana: Elkhart, circa 1920; Lafayette, 1997; South Bend, 1970, 1996, n.d. (Box 1046, Folder 15)
      - Iowa: General, 1910s?; Ames, 1996; Burlington, 1976; Fort Dodge, 1975; Shelby, 1918; Washington, 1996 (Box 1046, Folder 16)
      - Kansas, 1918 (Box 1046, Folder 17)
      - Kentucky: General, circa 1930s-40; Louisville, 1930s, n.d.; Versailles, 1937 (Box 1046a, Folder 1)
      - Louisiana: New Orleans, 1964-circa 1995 (Box 1046a, Folder 2)
      - Maine: Bangor, n.d.; Farmington, 1919-1920; Portland, 1997 (Box 1046, Folder 3)
      - Maryland: Baltimore, 1974, 1993, n.d. (Box 1046, Folder 4)
      - Massachusetts
        - Boston, 1971-94, n.d. (Box 1046, Folder 5)
        - Brockton, 1997; Cambridge, 1984, 1996; Newburyport, 1998; New Bedford, 1984; Worcester, 2002? (Box 1046, Folder 6)
      - Michigan: Bay County, 1996, n.d.; Detroit, 1930; Flint, 1971; Mayville, 1910s? (Box 1046, Folder 7)
      - Minnesota: Minneapolis, 1896, circa 1990s-96; St. Paul, circa 1960s; West Duluth, circa 1976, n.d. (Box 1047, Folder 1)
      - Mississippi: General, n.d.; Attala County, n.d.; Bolton, 1974; Brookhaven, 1976; Durant, 1937; Gulfport, 1937, n.d.; Jackson, 1981 (Box 1047, Folder 2)
      - Missouri: Kansas City, 1987, 1998; Springfield, c. 1918; St Louis, c. 1910-30, 1996, n.d. (Box 1047, Folder 3)
      - Nebraska: Seward, 1996 (Box 1047, Folder 4)
      - New Jersey
        - Bergen County, 1975; Elizabeth, 1920; Essex, n.d.; Holendel, circa 1918; Orange, 1971, 1983; Passaic, 1939-40; Plainfield, 1983-84; Red Bank, circa 1920 (Box 1047, Folder 5)
        - Summit, circa 1960, 1983; Trenton, 1995 (Box 1047, Folder 6)
      - New Mexico: Albuquerque, 1980, n.d. (Box 1047, Folder 7)
      - New York
        - Adirondack Foothills, n.d.; Altamont, 1920; Binghamton, n.d.; Brooklyn, 1904-1936, 1980-96; Buffalo, circa 1920-25, n.d.; Chautauqua, circa 1919, 1980-81; Greene County, c. 1910s; Newburgh, 1996? (Box 1047, Folder 8)
        - City of New York, 1898, c. 1960-96 (Box 1047, Folder 9)
        - Queens, 1993; Rochester, n.d.; Schenectady, 1993; Utica, circa 1985; White Plains, 1974-96 (Box 1047, Folder 10)
      - North Carolina: General, circa 1910s; Charlotte, 1976, 1987, 1998, n.d.; Greensboro, n.d.; High Point, 1996; Wake County, 1992, n.d.; Winston-Salem, 1971, 1996 (Box 1047, Folder 11)
      - Ohio: Akron, n.d.; Cincinnati, circa 1981-98; Cleveland, circa 1918, circa 1960s, n.d.; Columbus, 1987; Dayton, 1975, n.d.; Greene County, c. 1913, n.d.; Licking County, 1984; Springfield, 1975; Toledo, n.d.; Warren, 1995; Youngstown, circa 1980-97; Zanesville, n.d. (Box 1047, Folder 12)
      - Oklahoma: Enid, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 1)
      - Oregon: Portland, 1984, n.d.; Salem, 1982 (Box 1048, Folder 2)
      - Pennsylvania
        - General, circa 1910s; Allegheny, 1988; Bucks County, circa 1960; Germantown, 1913; Gettysburg, 1986; Lancaster, n.d.; Philadelphia, 1961, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 3)
        - Pittsburgh, 1919, circa 1960-96, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 4)
        - York, 1951, 1984 (Box 1048, Folder 5)
      - Puerto Rico, 1946-93, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 6)
      - Rhode Island: Providence, 1946, circa 1950; Woonsocket, circa 1990-96 (Box 1048, Folder 7)
      - South Carolina: Charlotte, 1999; Greenville, circa 1910s, 1911, 1996-98, n.d.; Sumter, 1964-66 (Box 1048, Folder 8)
      - South Dakota: Huron, n.d.; Sioux Falls, 1999 (Box 1048, Folder 9)
      - Tennessee: Memphis, 1975, 1982; Nashville, 1929, 1985 (Box 1048, Folder 10)
      - Texas
        - Abilene, 1997; Austin, circa 1990s; Dallas, circa 1920, 1982, 1996; El Paso, 1992, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 11)
        - Fort Worth, 1982; Houston, circa 1910s, 1990-96 (Box 1048, Folder 12)
        - Paris/Lamar, 1966-67; San Antonio, 1996-99 (Box 1048, Folder 13)
      - Utah: Salt Lake City, 1982 (Box 1048, Folder 14)
      - Virginia: Newport News, 1992; Norfolk, 1996 (Box 1048, Folder 15)
      - Washington: Bellingham, 1914, 1974, n.d.; Bremerton, circa 1910s; Seattle, circa 1984; Spokane, 1996; Olympia, n.d. (Box 1048, Folder 16)
      - West Virginia: General, circa 1971; Buckhannon, 1966-67 (Box 1048, Folder 17)
      - Wisconsin: Dodge County, circa 1920, n.d.; Green Bay, n.d.; Racine, 1955-56; Waukesha, 1997; Wausau, 1990 (Box 1048, Folder 18)
  - OVERSIZE PRINTS
    - Subseries A. General and History
      - Anniversaries: Service in Commemoration of 25th Anniversary of the dedication of 600 Lexington Ave., 2 Dec 1937 (Box 1049, Folder 1)
      - World YWCA
        - Interior of British and American YWCA Home, Paris, circa 1890s; World's Executive Committee meeting, Washington, DC, 1924; World Council Meetings, group photographs: Oxford, England, n.d.; Washington, DC, 1941; Phoenix, Arizona, 1987 (Box 1049)
    - Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office
      - National Board and Staff: -Budget Reviewing Committee meeting at Mrs. Lewis H. Laphams's house, 1920s (modern print) -White House and Good Housekeeping gathering of presidents of women's organizations, 1974 -Pen and ink drawing of Grace Dodge (head and shoulders in an oval) by John J. Shayn, circa 1926-appears to have been made from the standard photograph of her -Black and white photograph of a painted portrait of Mabel Cratty, n.d. (Box 1049, Folder 2)
      - Buildings and Properties: Library at 7 East 15th St., New York, NY (Box 1049)
    - Subseries C. Conferences and Conventions
      - Conferences: Central Field Conference, Hotel Sherman, Chicago; 1919 Conventions: American Committee National Convention, Scranton, PA, 1891; 21st Convention, Recognition of 71 new associations, 1958 (Box 1049, Folder 3)
    - Subseries D. International Work
      - China: School of Physical Education, Shaghai, 1923 (3 photos); Hangchow: graduation exercises, 1923-24; YWCA membership party, 1925 (Box 1049, Folder 4)
      - Argentina: Mar del Platte, 1960s? (2 photos); Burma: gymnastics class, Rangoon, 1931; Japan: Girls Higher Normal School, Tokyo, n.d.; Far Eastern Regional Conference, Columbo, Ceylon, 1936 (Box 1049, Folder 5)
    - Subseries E. Program
      - Advocacy: contact sheet, Emily's List luncheon during Inaugural Week, 1993 Personnel and Training: American Committee, Secretaries' Training Institute, fall term 1904 (Box 1050, Folder 1)
      - Sports and Fitness: miscellaneous photos, 1950s-60s (Box 1050)
      - Constitutent Groups
        - Altamont Industrial Conference, 1920 (Box 1050)
        - Teen Age and Younger Girls: Iowa State High School Conference of the YWCA, Ames, Iowa, 1917; Girl Reserves Conference, Seabeck, 1925; Y-Teen Conferences, 1971-73 (Box 1050, Folder 2)
      - War Work and Defense Services
        - World War I
          - Hostess Houses: Interior of 41st St. and Lexington Ave., NY City; Ellington Field (Texas) Hostess House staff group, 14 Sep 1918; army camp (idenfication broken off) with Hostess House site marked; exterior of Hostess House, Michigan, 1918; tea in a YWCA Hut; Industrial Service Center Library, Chicago; Yeomanettes, Puget Sound Navy Yard (Box 1050, Folder 3)
          - Women working, Great Britain press photographs (Box 1050, Folder 4)
    - Subseries F. Student Work
      - Conferences, 1910s (Box 1050, Folder 5)
      - Conferences, 1920s-40s (Box 1050, Folder 6)
      - Conferences, 1950s (Box 1051, Folder 1)
    - Subseries G. Community Associations
      - Conferences: Central Region City, Lake Geneva, 1920; Eastern Region City, Silver Bay, 1920; Southern Region, 1928 (partial); Seabeck [Western] Community, 1920 (Box 1051, Folder 2)
      - Buildings: Buffalo, NY, circa 1889; large color prints, 1980s: San Francisco, CA; Fort Wayne, IN; Burlington, Dubuque, and Marshalltown, IA; Flint, MI; Minneapolis, MN; Summit, NJ; Omaha, NE; Greensboro and Winston-Salem, NC; McKeesport, PA; El Paso, TX; Seattle, WA; unidentified (Box 1051, Folder 3-9)
      - Groups: Rochester, NY, circa 1890s; Charlotte, NC, 1938; Honolulu, HI, 1940s; St. Louis, MO, 1950s (Box 1051, Folder 10)
  - MISCELLANEOUS OVERSIZE
    - International Work (Box 1052)
      - Foldable photo displays: China, Esthonia and Latvia, India (2), Near East, South America, 1920s (Box 1052)
      - Album, YWCA of Warsaw, Poland, n.d. (Box 1052)
    - Subseries E. Program
      - Constituent Groups
        - Estes Park (Colorado) Girl Reserve Conference: photo album, 1923-24 (Box 1052A)
        - We-go-u-go Industrial Club of the Denver YWCA: photo album/scrapbook, 1923-25 (Box 1052A)
    - GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES
      - Grace Dodge at Greystone, Riverdale (Box 1053, Folder 1)
      - Grace Dodge and two women standing outside (Box 1053, Folder 2)
      - Chinese bride (Box 1053, Folder 3)
      - In a Chinese cart (Box 1053, Folder 4)
      - Preparing for opening of YWCA, Riga, Latvia (Box 1053, Folder 5)
      - Site of 600 Lexington Ave, 1911 (Box 1053, Folder 6)
- SERIES II. SLIDES
  - Subseries A. General and History
    - Lists and general information re YWCA slide collection, 1989-96, n.d. (Box 1054, Folder 1)
    - "Historical Slides Suitable to adaptation to other types of presentations," YWCA Archives, 1986: list and slides (Box 1054, Folder 2)
    - Anniversary, 135th, 1993-94
      - Reception at Leadership Development Center, 1994 (Box 1054, Folder 3)
      - Exhibit "Women First for 135 Years"
        - Openings and other events, 1993-94 (Box 1054, Folder 4)
        - Images used in exhibit
          - Theme I. YWCA Women First in Housing (Box 1054, Folder 5)
          - Theme II. Positive Health-A YWCA Concept (Box 1054, Folder 6)
          - Theme III. YWCA Women First in the Workplace (Box 1054, Folder 7)
          - Theme IV. YWCA Takes a Stand (Box 1054, Folder 8)
          - Theme V. YWCA Women First in Diversity (Box 1054, Folder 9)
          - Theme VI. YWCA Women First in the Family of Nations (Box 1054, Folder 10)
          - Theme VII. YWCA Women First in Leadership (Box 1054, Folder 11)
        - Images used in exhibition catalog (Box 1054, Folder 12)
        - Images not used (Box 1054, Folder 13)
    - Events, unidentified (Box 1054, Folder 14)
    - Groups
      - Identified (Box 1054, Folder 15)
      - Unidentified (Box 1054, Folder 16)
    - Individuals
      - Identified (Box 1054, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified (Box 1054, Folder 18)
    - Logos, posters, symbols, artifacts (Box 1054, Folder 19)
    - World YWCA
      - "The YWCA as a Lay Ecumenical Movement": script and slides, 1965 (Box 1054, Folder 20)
      - Council
        - 1971 (Ghana) "Shots from the World YWCA Family Album": script and slides (Box 1054, Folder 21)
        - 1983 (Singapore)
          - General (Box 1055, Folder 1)
          - Script of presentation at National Board Meeting, Jan 1984 [no slides] (Box 1055, Folder 2)
        - 1987 (United States)
          - "Slide Set": script and slides (Box 1055, Folder 3)
          - General (Box 1055, Folder 4)
          - Cabaret (Box 1055, Folder 5)
          - "Faces" (Box 1055, Folder 6)
          - Grand Canyon Trip (Box 1055, Folder 7)
          - Peace Site Dedication (Box 1055, Folder 8)
          - Reception (Box 1055, Folder 9)
          - "Staged Shots" (Box 1055, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office
    - National Board: Meetings, 1979, 1980, 1988 (Box 1055, Folder 11-13)
    - Buildings and Properties
      - 600 Lexington Ave., New York City, entrance, 1962 (Box 1055, Folder 14)
      - Leadership Development Center, Phoenix, Arizona
        - General (Box 1055, Folder 15)
        - Dedication, 1983 (Box 1055, Folder 16)
    - Finance and Development
      - General, 1982, n.d. (Box 1055, Folder 17)
      - Ford Foundation breakfast, n.d. [pre-1980] (Box 1055, Folder 18)
      - National Support slide presentation: script and slides, 1959, 1962 (Box 1055, Folder 19-20)
      - Tribute to Women in Industry Awards, 1978 (Box 1056, Folder 1)
      - U.N. Luncheon and reception with Paul Newman, n.d. (Box 1056, Folder 2)
      - Waldorf reception, n.d. [pre-1980] (Box 1056, Folder 3)
      - World Service Council reception at Carter Center during Convention, 1991 (Box 1056, Folder 4)
    - Library and Archives: miscellaneous historical visuals, posters, etc. (Box 1056, Folder 4a)
    - Publicity
      - "It Takes All Kinds to Make a World,"1980
        - Script and publicity materials (Box 1056, Folder 5)
        - Slides (Box 1056, Folder 6)
      - YWCA merchandise, 1980 (Box 1056, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C. Conferences and Conventions
    - Conferences: Written material: "Hints for Successful Use of the Regional Conference Slides," 1955 [no slides] (Box 1056, Folder 8)
    - Conventions
      - General, 1976-93, n.d. (Box 1056, Folder 9)
      - 1961 22nd: script and slides for session "Program Development and Expansion in Community YWCAs" by Barbara Abel (Box 1056, Folder 10)
      - 196724th: script for slide presentation about Convention [no slides] (Box 1056, Folder 11)
      - 27th, 1976
        - "The YWCA Convention: the Bridge Between Past and Future:" script and slides for use at convention preparation Meetings (Box 1056, Folder 12)
        - "Freedom to Be... Power to Move: YWCA of the USA 27th Triennial Convention June 1976," script and slides for presentation about the 1976 Convention, [see also Record Group 10. Audio Materials] (Box 1056, Folder 13)
      - 197928th: general slides (Box 1056, Folder 14)
      - 29th, 1982
        - "The YWCA of the U.S.A.: The Sum of its Parts," script and slides for use at Convention preparation meetings, Jan 1982 (Box 1056, Folder 15)
        - "Making the Difference: An Historical YWCA Commitment," script and slides for slide-audio revolving show by Elizabeth Norris at YWCA Exhibit Booth (Box 1056, Folder 16)
        - General slides taken at Convention (Box 1056, Folder 17)
        - Script and slides for presentation about 1982 Convention (Box 1056, Folder 18)
      - 30th, 1985: Script and slides of Convention Overview for use at Convention Preparation Meetings, 1984 (Box 1056, Folder 19)
      - 1994 33rd: general slides taken at Convention (Box 1057, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries D. International Work
    - "Training Makes the Difference! Trainees at work in ten countries of the Far East": script and slides, 30 Jun 1959 (Box 1057, Folder 4-5)
    - "A YWCA Journey": script and slides of the Rockefeller-National Geographic trip to YWCAs around the world, 1963 (Box 1057, Folder 6)
    - "YWCA World Fellowship in Action in Ethiopia": script and slides, May 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 7)
    - "YWCAs in Far Places Help Early School Leavers": script and slides, Jun 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 8)
    - "YWCA Camps Around the World," script and slides, Sep 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 9)
    - "The YWCA of Guadalajara, Mexico": script only, 1967 (Box 1057, Folder 10)
    - "South American Journey": script and slides, Feb 1967 (Box 1057, Folder 11)
    - "Visiting the YWCA Family-Around the World": script and slides, Aug 1968 (Box 1057, Folder 12)
    - "A Power to Do: The World YWCA is Woven of Many Threads": script only, 1973 (Box 1057, Folder 13)
    - "A South Pacific Journey": script and slides re Mary French Rockefeller's trip to the South Pacific with her husband and National Geographic photographers, Sep 1973 (Box 1057, Folder 14)
    - "A Celebration of Women": script and slides re dedication of the YWCA Window of Thanksgiving at the Washington Cathedral, 1978 (Box 1057, Folder 15)
    - "Breaking Barriers": script and slides by World Relations, Apr 1979 (Box 1057, Folder 16)
    - Slides of YWCAs in other countries, general, 1963-87, n.d. (Box 1057, Folder 17)
    - Slides taken by Helene Mosier
      - Africa (Box 1058)
        - General, 1966-72, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 1)
        - Liberia, 1969-72, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 2-3)
      - South America, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 5)
  - Subseries E. Program
    - Advocacy
      - General, 1976-93, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 6)
      - ERA Demonstration and March, Washington, DC, 1982 (Box 1058, Folder 7)
    - Training: general, 1970-88, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 8)
    - Constituent Groups
      - Employed Women
        - Job Corps-YWCA Extension Residence Program
          - General, 1973 (Box 1058, Folder 9)
          - Courses in Beauty Culture, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 10)
        - New Jobs for Women, Philadelphia YWCA, 1970s (Box 1058, Folder 11)
      - Teen Age and Younger Girls
        - General (Box 1058, Folder 12)
        - Conferences, 1970s, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 13)
      - Young Adults
        - Eastern Region Young Adult Conference, 1957 (Box 1058, Folder 14)
        - Young Women Committed to Action Assembly, 1978 (Box 1058, Folder 15)
    - Subjects
      - Camping and Outdoor Recreation: National Youth Conference on Conservation and Natural Beauty, Jun 1966 (Box 1059, Folder 1)
      - Health
        - General (Box 1059, Folder 2)
        - Food Nutrition and Safety, Pittsburgh YWCA, 1974-75 (Box 1059, Folder 3)
        - ENCOREplus Slide Presentation: script and slides, 1995 (Box 1059, Folder 4)
      - Recreation (Box 1059, Folder 5)
      - Religion: Mission of the YWCA: script and slides, 1977 (Box 1059, Folder 6)
      - Sports (Box 1059, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F. Student Work
    - General, n.d. (Box 1059, Folder 8-10)
    - Conferences and Council
      - General, 1951, n.d. (Box 1059, Folder 11)
      - Lake Geneva Conference: script and slides, 1957 (Box 1059, Folder 12)
      - National Student Council, Coe College, 1978 (Box 1059, Folder 13)
    - "Albuquerque Project": script and slides for recruitment, 1965 (Box 1059, Folder 14)
    - Washington Student Citizenship Seminar, 1950 (Box 1059, Folder 15)
  - Subseries G. Community Associations
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1060, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified (Box 1060, Folder 2)
    - California (Box 1060, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut (Box 1060, Folder 4)
    - Florida (Box 1060, Folder 5)
    - Illinois (Box 1060, Folder 6)
    - Indiana (Box 1060, Folder 7)
    - Montana (Box 1060, Folder 8)
    - New Jersey: Maple Run Area Migrant Projects, summer 1964 (Box 1060, Folder 9)
    - New York: White Plains (Box 1060, Folder 10)
    - North Carolina (Box 1060, Folder 11)
    - Ohio (Box 1060, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 1060, Folder 13)